Dima Hordiienko

front-end developer (React.js)

Email: odinokun@gmail.com LinkedIn: @dmitry-gordienko

Phone/Whatsapp: +49 1516 440 5660 Github: https://github.com/Odinokun

Telegram: @odinokun Website/portfolio: http://odinokun.com

Current location: Ottawa, Canada

Skills

- React.js

- Redux

- JavaScript

TypeScript

- HTML (Pug)

- Css (Sass/Scss/Less)

Tools

- Material UI

- Tailwind

- Bootstrap

- Git

- Webpack

- Gulp

- Npm/Yarn/Pnpm

Summary

I have worked as a front-end developer for 8+ years, since 2014.

I have experience of working in large corporate teams and in small startups. However, despite my experience in both large corporate teams and small startups, I prefer long-term working relationships and am not inclined to frequently change jobs.

My superpower is the ability to transform a design of any complexity into a correctly functioning website.

I love the frontend because new technologies appear in it every day. The work of a front-end developer was very well described by Lewis Carroll "My dear, here we must run as fast as we can, just to stay in place. And if you wish to go anywhere you must run twice as fast as that."

Experience

NDA - (2022 - present)

Position: front-end developer

Description:

A platform that specializes in the creation and sale of NFT tokens, unique digital assets based on the blockchain.

What I do:

- handle the design and layout of the user interface, as well as contribute to the overall project design
- develop and create new React components that enhance functionality and enable user interaction
- use tools like GSAP to craft captivating and smooth animations that breathe life into the project's interface
- work with various APIs and engage with backend systems to ensure the proper functioning and logic of the project

Technologies:

React.js, TypeScript, Material UI, GSAP

EpicentrK - (2020 - 2022)

Position: front-end developer

Description:

The biggest trade platform in Ukraine: building materials, FMCG, and others. They own a network of big supermarkets and a big online store (https://epicentrk.ua)

What I do:

- created new pages and sections in the online store, ensuring convenient navigation and expanding functionality to enhance the user experience
- optimized the existing portion of the store, conducting performance analysis, optimizing code, and improving page loading for increased speed and meeting user demands
- developed separate landing pages for one-time and seasonal promotions, as well as sales, to attract customer attention, increase conversion rates, and boost sales.
- expanded internal tools such as CRM and admin panel, improving their functionality, adding new features, and facilitating efficient data management and analysis for the store team

Technologies:

HTML/Pug, Css/Scss, JavaScript, Jquery, Vue.js

Front-end developer (self employed) - (2014 - 2020)

I made over 150 websites of different levels of complexity - from landing pages and email campaigns to big corporate sites and online stores. I also provided technical support and optimization for existing websites.

Here are some of these projects:

4Deluxe - https://4deluxe-whirlpool.de

German network online store for the sale of swimming pools

- was responsible for the entire scope of work related to project frontend development
- handled the setup and integration of the form submission mechanism
- was accountable for the development and implementation of the product filtering logic

Technologies:

HTML/Pug, Css/Scss, JavaScript, Jquery

FlowerLand Decor - https://flowerlanddecor.com

USA florist-decor service

- was responsible for the entire scope of work related to project frontend development
- handled the setup and integration of the form submission mechanism

Technologies:

HTML/Pug, Css/Scss, JavaScript, Jquery

Kozyris&Co - https://kozyris.com

A web studio specializing in website development, support, and maintenance.

- was responsible for the entire scope of work related to project frontend development
- created page animations using tools such as GSAP and Barba.js. Barba.js helped me achieve smooth transitions between pages, creating the impression of a seamless single-page application (SPA) rather than a traditional website

Technologies:

HTML/Pug, Css/Scss, JavaScript, GSAP, Barba.js

Education

Kyiv University of Tourism, Economics and Law (Ukraine) - Bachelor's degree in law

Additional courses

Web Development for Advanced (Loftschool)
Complete JavaScript Course (Loftschool)
React Developer Course (IT Incubator School) - in progress

Languages

English - Intermediate (B1)

Russian - Native speaker

Ukrainian - Native speaker

Germany - Pre-Intermediate (A2)